{
    "id": "7f66052f94594beda448e053e67e5207",
    "title": "Tenses Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "He ……………………….. his hand.",
            "description": "Raise is transitive. It takes an object. Rise is intransitive.",
            "answers": [
                "rose",
                "raised"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "Don’t blow it up too much. You will ……………………….. the balloon.",
            "description": "All three forms of burst are burst.",
            "answers": [
                "burst",
                "bursted",
                "bursten"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "He ………………………… in the morning.",
            "description": "When we say when something happened, we use the simple past. ",
            "answers": [
                "called",
                "has called",
                "had called"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "We ………………………….. all of our friends.",
            "description": "The present perfect is preferred to express ideas like these. When there is no time reference, we use the present perfect to talk about finished events. ",
            "answers": [
                "invited",
                "have invited",
                "had invited"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "Where ……………………………….. all this while?",
            "description": "The present perfect is used to talk about an action or situation that started in the past and has continued up to the present. ",
            "answers": [
                "have you been",
                "had you been",
                "were you"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "Trouble began shortly after he ……………………………….",
            "description": "The past perfect is more correct here because it refers to the earlier of the two actions however, the simple past is also possible here because the time expression after clearly shows which action occurred first. ",
            "answers": [
                "arrived",
                "had arrived",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "I ………………………… from them for a long time.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "didn't hear",
                "haven't heard",
                "hadn't heard"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "I will ……………………… you something but keep it a secret.",
            "description": "Before a personal object, use tell.",
            "answers": [
                "tell",
                "say"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "Neither of the passengers ……………………….. tickets.",
            "description": "Use a singular verb after neither. ",
            "answers": [
                "has",
                "have"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "The flowers on this plant …………………………… no fragrance.",
            "description": "Here the subject is the plural noun flowers. ",
            "answers": [
                "has",
                "have"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "None of them ………………………….. present at the party.",
            "description": "Use a singular verb after none. ",
            "answers": [
                "was",
                "were"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "Germs ………………………………. in cold weather.",
            "description": "Use the simple present to talk about facts. ",
            "answers": [
                "thrive",
                "are thriving",
                "have thriven"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        }
    ]
}